♪♪
It's all here.
Everything you wanted,
from automatic weapons
to Redeye missiles.
Usual mint condition.
Now, this really
going to be it for you?
No more orders?
This is it.
Where's the rig?
I didn't bring it.
How'd you get out here?
- I jogged.
- No kidding?
How you going to get back?
I don't feel
comfortable about this.
I don't like putting somebody
on the stand I
haven't talked to.
She only got in this morning,
and she's leaving
this afternoon.
So, uh... um...
Ms. Anderson...
Mrs. Anderson? Yeah.
Uh, would you tell
us where you were
at approximately 1:30 on
the afternoon of September 2?
Uh-huh. I was at the parking lot
at the Westlake branch of
Monument Savings and Loan.
Uh-huh. And what did you
see while you were there?
Yeah, I saw a man come
running out of the bank
who was carrying a
briefcase in one hand
and pulling off a wig and
sunglasses with the other.
He-he just stuffed
everything in his briefcase,
and he kept right on running.
Huh. Uh, uh, would...
He had long, wavy blond hair
and thick lips.
Thick lips?
Yeah, real thick.
See, that's not the guy.
See how thin his lips are?
Yeah, he does have
moderately thin lips.
- Doesn't he?
- Yeah.
Ordinarily, I don't notice
the lip size on a man.
I guess that's
because I'm a man.
Sure. I mean, that...
that certainly makes sense.
But see, I'm a girl,
and lip size is one
of the very first things
that I notice, especially
when they're thick.
- Uh-huh. Good.
- Isn't it?
Yeah, I mean, he is not the guy.
I don't even know
why he's on trial,
because the real bank robber
has blond hair and thick lips.
- Thick lips.
- Very thick.
And that man over there
has dark hair and very thin lips.
Thin lips.
Uh, Your Honor, might I
have a word with my client?
Go ahead, Mr. Matlock.
You're dead.
What?
You know this girl,
and you put her up
to this, Mr. Thin Lips.
I wouldn't do that to her.
She's a friend of mine.
She... she volunteered.
You're dead.
- No further questions.
- But...
You're dead.
Your witness.
Thank you, Your Honor.
This man whom you
saw run from the bank...
What color raincoat
was he wearing?
Um... gray?
Well, the bank teller
whom he robbed at gunpoint
testified it was navy blue.
Well, maybe it was reversible.
You're dead, and
I hate you for it.
Mrs. Hawkins.
Mrs. Hawkins!
You lost your case, didn't you?
- Mrs. Hawkins...
- I knew you were going
- to lose that case.
- Mrs. Hawkins...
I didn't want to say anything,
but, uh, I knew
from your horoscope.
- Mrs. Hawkins...
- If you'd just ask.
Now you got a bad mark
against you with the courthouse.
Mrs. Hawkins, never
mind about that now.
Now, when you... when
you came to work for me,
I made a... a big deal about not
messing with stuff on my desk.
I can't find anything.
Mr. Matlock, your
desk was a sight.
All I did was put
things in order.
I don't want things in order.
I want them left
just as they are.
I was working on
a brief last night.
Had "Hartsell and Pruitt" on it.
Now it's gone.
Well, how was I to know?
Mr. Matlock, I worked
this way for 15 years
for Mr. Gaskins,
God rest his soul,
and he never once complained.
And I did everything for him...
Planning, arranging...
Right up to the end.
I even chose the
suit he was laid out in.
Well, that won't be
such a problem here.
See, I only wear this one
type of suit, and this is it.
All you got to do
is choose the one
that just came back
from the cleaners.
Or not. It won't make
much difference then.
A dark shade is
more appropriate.
I'm not buying a dark
suit for that one occasion.
You could always rent.
If I rent,
I guess they take it off
me right after the service
and stick me in
the ground naked.
I don't want to go
see Mr. Jesus naked.
Ben.
What?
You want to open the door?
Hi, Mrs. Hawkins.
- Hello.
- Ben.
Well, I said, "What?"
Plane tickets.
To where?
Remember? You
promised the publisher
of the Los Angeles
Chronicle that you'd defend
one of his reporters when
his contempt trial came up.
But I just lost a case and
I'm starting another one.
I'll get a continuance.
The contempt trial
starts tomorrow.
Well, I guess I did promise.
Oh, I guess I'd better go pack.
How important is this case?
- What?
- Don't go.
What are you talking about?
You're Gemini.
Don't go.
Mrs. Hawkins...
All right, don't listen to me,
but here's your
horoscope for today,
and remember, this day started
with you already losing a case.
"Your lunar aspect does
not coincide with travel.
"Business call suggests trip.
"Hold off.
"Be diplomatic and interested,
but avoid becoming involved.
"Entertain at home tonight.
"You'll be complimented
on appearance.
Feature colors."
I'll go pack.
Can't you stop him?
What's your sign?
Um... Aquarius?
Oh, that's perfect.
You're compatible with Gemini.
- Talk to him.
- Mrs. Hawkins,
- I really don't think...
- You know what Geminis are like.
They're dependent on others.
They need us.
They're always calling for help.
Help!
Where are my shirts?
Your attention, please...
You canceled my flight?
Equipment problems.
I'm booking you on Flight 532.
Departs at 9:45 from Gate 3C.
That's three hours from now.
I'm not waiting around
here three hours.
I'll use another airline.
This is our super bonanza
weekend discount fare.
No other airline
can come close to it.
You mean it'll cost me
more to use another airline?
Much more.
Dallas, St. Louis
or San Francisco,
please contact the airline...
Excuse me, please.
That can't be right.
I'm supposed to be
in business class.
Please sit down, sir,
you're blocking the aisle.
Oh, well... Ma'am.
You couldn't get here
five minutes earlier?
Excuse me.
What's the count?
All right. Thanks.
You lost my bag.
Fill this out, please.
How could you lose my bag?
You had three hours
to put it on the airplane.
If we don't get your bag
to you within 24 hours,
you'll receive a
free round-trip ticket
to any city we fly to.
Now... which suitcase
looks like yours?
Welcome to Los Angeles
International Airport.
Shuttle buses available
for the downtown area...
I know, Mrs. Hawkins.
I know.
Well, I warned you, didn't I?
Didn't your horoscope tell you?
You're lucky you
only lost your luggage.
You could have
crashed, you could have...
Well, I'm here now,
but I need some clothes.
Send a suit and-and some
shirts, and s... and underwear
and socks.
And whatever else you do today,
for heaven's sake, avoid
contact with a Capricorn.
Stay away from Capricorn.
Right. No Capricorns.
And I don't care what
else I have to focus on.
Just send the clothes.
Okay, I'm ready.
Well, Mr. Matlock...
It is Matlock, isn't it?
Yeah, yeah.
Mr. Matlock, I'm sorry.
It seems that we have...
You gave my room away?
Well, since you neither arrived,
nor called by 10:00
p.m. last night,
we gave your room
to somebody else.
At 10:00 p.m. last night, I
was 40,000 feet in the air.
I'm due in court in two hours.
I need to shave, shower,
and I want my room!
Please, sir, lower your voice.
Not until I get my room!
Have a good one.
Yeah, you, too, Buehler.
Oh.
Oh. Have you got
a styptic pencil?
Huh?
You know those white things
for when you cut yourself?
Perdón, Señor, no
entiendo Io que dice,
y no tengo tiempo
contestar las preguntas,
porque tengo que trabajar.
I realize this is highly
irregular, Your Honor.
I have been acting as
counsel to Mr. Thorndike
on a temporary basis only,
and since the man who
was to represent him
in this matter seems, at
the moment, to be missing...
Ben Matlock for the defense.
I'm sorry I'm late, Your Honor.
Got here as soon as I could.
Mr. Matlock, if
you're quite ready,
let's get started.
Uh, may I have a brief
recess to confer with my client?
No.
An hour at the most, maybe two?
Mr. Matlock, this case has
been continued four times.
I frankly am sick and tired
of seeing it on my calendar.
I will tolerate no more delays.
But, Your Honor...
The defendant, William
Thorndike, is charged
with three separate counts
of willfully refusing
to answer questions
after this court's denial
of his claim of immunity
from disclosure.
Your Honor, please.
Mr. Matlock, I
understand that in Atlanta
you have something
of a celebrity status,
but I want to assure you
that that will get you
nowhere in my courtroom.
Now, I don't want to hear
another word out of you
until the prosecution has
presented its arguments.
Is that perfectly clear?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Shepard, you may begin.
No, sir, I can't
do it. It's not right.
Mr. Matlock.
I can't let you
penalize my client...
Mr. Matlock, sit down.
Just because my plane
was late, I lost my luggage,
- and my room got all screwed up.
- Sit down and be quiet
or I will find you in contempt.
My client has a
constitutional right
to adequate
counsel, and right now
- there's no way in
hell - Mr. Matlock?
The word "adequate"
can be applied to me.
- You are in contempt.
- Huh?
Bailiff, you are instructed
to take Mr. Matlock
into immediate custody
and place him in lockup
until such time as a hearing
on his own contempt
charges may be set.
What am I supposed
to give to my client...?!
Man, don't know
nothing, you know?
What's your sign?
Huh?
Your sign. You know,
astrology, your horoscope.
Oh, that. Capricorn.
Hmm.
Mr. Matlock?
Hearing's over.
Judge Price rescinded his order.
Oh.
Guess he just wanted
to teach you a lesson.
Well, what happened after
they threw me out of there?
Well, Judge Price granted
another continuance.
When's the next hearing?
Well, he said he wasn't going
to put it back on his calendar
until he was, quote,
"damned good and ready."
It's an outrage to my client.
Oh, well, I really don't
think he much cares.
Oh.
So, what are you gonna do now?
Well, one thing
I'm not gonna do...
I'm not making
another trip out here.
Mr. Matlock, if you're
thinking of going to see him,
there's something I
ought to tell you first.
What?
You've got toilet
paper on your face.
Oh.
Mm-hmm.
Uh, you can't beat that.
We're wasting time here.
We got to talk.
Discussion's closed.
Raymond's right, Daryl.
He's stated his position,
he's not gonna budge.
Further talk is pointless.
What about you?
You're just gonna
roll over, too?
I think Raymond is wrong.
I think I can beat that.
Hey, Judge Price?!
Hey.
Your Honor, we've got to talk.
You're interrupting our game.
I can see that.
How would you
like to go back to jail
on a harassment
charge this time?
Judge Price, the
Constitution says
that my client has the
right to a speedy trial.
You cannot, and I will not
discuss your client's
case at this time.
This has nothing to do with
my client, and you know it.
You're madder than hell at me.
Now, you will hear this case,
or I will file a complaint.
You're asking for trouble.
Trouble is a two-way
street, Your Honor.
Are you threatening
me, Mr. Matlock?
I'm trying to do my job.
My chambers, 7:00 tonight.
Settle it now.
My chambers, 7:00 tonight!
All right. Your chambers, 7:00.
What the hell are
you doing here?
Just wanted to talk.
I've made up my mind, Walker.
Yeah.
I know.
Too bad.
Uh, excuse me, I'm
here to see Judge Price.
Yes, he came in
about ten minutes ago.
- Okay.
- Fourth floor.
Fourth floor.
Right through there.
Judge Price?
♪♪
Yeah.
A drink.
What'll it be?
Uh... one like that.
Coming right up.
Hey, hey, did...
did you-did you-did you
know Judge Raymond Price?
A personal friend of mine.
Yeah?
He's dead.
Yeah, yeah.
He-he was... he
was... he was a jackass,
a real jackass, but he...
he didn't deserve to be dead.
Mmm.
That'll be $2.50.
Okay.
I guess I'll have to
open an account.
Guess again.
♪♪
Where... where's your money?
I don't know.
Don't-don't take my...
Don't take my watch!
Mr. Matlock.
Lieutenant Judd Myerson.
As you know, you have
the right to remain silent.
Anything you say, can
and will be used against you.
You can forget all that part.
What's on your mind?
Let's talk about last night.
I don't remember last night.
At about 11:30, you
entered Angels Tavern.
You ordered a drink.
You asked the bartender if he
knew Judge Raymond T. Price.
Then you told him
the judge was dead.
And then you
called him a jackass.
I did?
You went to see the
judge about 7:00 last night.
Do you remember that?
Yeah.
Yeah. He was lying on the floor.
He looked like he was dead.
He was dead all right.
He was murdered.
Do you know who did it?
Do you?
Let's see, I...
I saw the judge
lying on the floor.
And then... somebody...
somebody hit me and choked me.
I-I must have blacked out.
Wait a minute,
I saw somebody in the
mirror, just before he hit me.
Must have been the murderer.
Where-where are your mug books?
If I can see his picture,
I might recognize him.
That won't be necessary.
I want to see those
books right now.
According to passport records,
the only fingerprints on the
murder weapon are yours.
You had a loud disagreement
with the judge in
court yesterday.
You were seen entering the
courthouse less than an hour
before the body was discovered.
And you told the
bartender at Angels Tavern
that the judge was dead.
It may be hard to
believe, Mr. Matlock,
but that makes you
our prime suspect.
You've got to be kidding.
The D.A. isn't.
♪♪
All right, come on,
keep it moving, guys.
Ben, Ben.
I can't believe this.
Are you all right?
- Yeah.
- We're gonna get you out of here
as soon as we can.
We're fifth on the docket.
Got some clean clothes
for you back at the hotel.
Oh. I'm glad you're here.
Come on, keep it moving.
The defendant's
not from this city
or even this state,
Your Honor, and to say
that he has no ties
to this community
is a gross understatement.
Hey, I've been a member
of the Bar in good standing
since before you knew
what the word "gross" meant!
Uh, Your Honor, my client,
as you may know, or by
now may have guessed,
is an attorney.
He's, uh, a member
of the Bar in five states.
His record and reputation
as an officer of the court in
all of them is unblemished.
It's absurd to
think that there's
any risk of flight here at all.
In fact, I recommend
that he be released
on his own recognizance.
My main concern here
is not the risk of flight.
This was a particularly
heinous crime.
A jurist was murdered...
A fellow jurist.
Bail is set at $250,000.
Next case.
$250,000?!
That's a quarter of a million!
- It's okay, Ben.
- It's not okay!
I'm not John Dillinger!
- $250,000.
- 250... Highway robbery!
You're John Dillinger!
Next case.
Empty 'em.
Hey!
You stole my watch!
- Oh, I-I-I'm sorry.
- Yeah? Yeah? Yeah?
You-you can have
it back. It's yours.
It's his!
See, I...
I didn't even... I
didn't even hock it.
I didn't have time to hock it.
See? It's a good thing that
I mugged you when I did.
No.
The way you were staggering
all over that neighborhood,
- you could have got killed.
- Yeah.
You were following me?
Uh, yeah, well, you
know, kind of casing you.
I picked you up right outside
of that there warehouse.
What warehouse?!
Uh, the one that you
went into with that guy.
What guy?!
Your buddy.
The guy who practically
dragged you in.
What did he look like?
What did he look like?!
Dark-dark hair,
brown-brown, big build.
Big.
Ben.
Bail's been posted.
Good.
Now let's see if you can
get bail for my friend here.
What's your name?
Sloan, Andrew Nathaniel
Ridgeway Sloan.
- Sloan.
Hi, Conrad. When
did you get here?
As soon as I could.
- You okay?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Conrad, Andrew Sloan.
This is a suite.
It's all they had.
Oh.
- This just came.
- Oh.
Airline found it in Anchorage.
Gave you a free
round-trip ticket.
Why don't you take a bath.
Right now, a nice hot
meal sounds better.
Well, here's a
room service menu.
Order anything I like?
Yeah.
- Bottle of wine.
- No wine.
Ben Matlock.
I'm calling to see
if the clothes I sent
got there all right.
Not yet, Mrs.
Hawkins, but it's okay.
Michelle brought me some.
I'm going to have more
clothes than I need now.
What floor are you on?
What?
I said what floor are you on?
Don't go above the second floor.
Mrs. Hawkins...
Listen to me... The
moon in your sign
warns against heights.
Hello?
Let me show you something.
Sure wish I had a little wine.
No wine.
Come in.
CI-Close the door.
That's why I was walking
around like a drunken sailor.
Oh, Ben.
You were shot up
with some kind of drug.
Yeah.
Did you get a blood test?
By the time I came
to, it was too late
and I was in jail.
So what does he
have to do with it?
I hope he can help
me find the killer.
There were only three people
who knew I was going to
the judge's office that night...
Those three fellas he
was playing golf with.
But it couldn't have been
one of them, 'cause I saw
the killer's face in the mirror.
So the killer had to be hired
by one of them, 'cause like I
say, they were the only ones
who knew I was
going to be there.
Did you get their names?
I have to call Lieutenant
Myerson back.
Better do that.
Uh, Ben, you need to wash.
Oh, yeah.
- Hey, Conrad.
- Yeah.
You know those, uh,
airplane tickets I threw away?
Oh, thanks.
- I'll just get this sterilized.
- Yeah.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to startle you.
Although, I wouldn't have
minded if I caught you.
Michelle Thomas.
You're representing the man
accused of murdering
Raymond Price.
Ben Matlock.
That's right.
Well, I-I'm not
complaining, mind you,
but, uh, what brings you here?
Well, according to the
Westhaven Country Club,
you played golf with Judge
Price the day he was murdered.
It was Friday.
The four of us always
played golf on Friday.
That means you knew
Mr. Matlock was going to be
seeing Judge Price that night.
Michelle, I want you
to take a look at this.
The four of us in Vietnam, 1968.
Green Berets.
Special Forces.
Missions into Cambodia mostly.
We trusted each other,
depended on each other
and put our lives on
the line for each other.
Friendships forged
during the heat of battle
last forever, believe me.
Well, thank you, Mr. Prescott.
Well, um, do you
have to run off so soon?
Um... gee, my next appointment
isn't for another 20 minutes.
I could give you a lesson.
Fly casting?
Whatever.
This is the warehouse.
- This?
- Yeah.
I was sleeping off my wine
under them there boxes.
Hiya, Tierney.
If-if you were asleep, how
could you see anything?
A car door slammed, woke me up.
Thought maybe it was
the cops so I looked out.
Saw that brown-haired
guy dragging you inside.
Oh. Oh.
What kind of car was he driving?
Dark.
Uh, not too big.
Not too small.
We must have just
missed somebody.
That was it. That
was the car I saw.
That must have been the guy.
Just tell me you
saw his license plate.
I saw his license plate,
but it was so fast
I couldn't catch it.
Wow.
Come on in. Make
yourself comfortable.
Please.
You know, I really
appreciate you squeezing me
into your schedule
like this, Dr. Lehman.
Well, you did indicate
that it was an emergency.
Could I...?
Certainly.
Never pictured myself in a
psychiatrist's office before.
I'm a nervous wreck.
I've been shaking
all over the place.
Got butterflies in my
stomach as big as elephants.
Well, any idea where
those butterflies come from?
Maybe.
See, I'm an investigator
for Ben Matlock.
The man who's been accused
of murdering Judge Price.
So it's up to me
to find evidence
that proves he didn't do it.
And I'm worried.
I mean, what if I can't do it?
What if I let him down?
Yeah. So I got to thinking,
what if Judge Price was
killed by someone who knew
they could frame Ben
Matlock for the murder?
Like say, one of
the three people
he played golf
with that afternoon.
Get out of here.
Don't I get 50 minutes?
I said get out of here!
You know, I feel better already.
Well, see, he had,
uh, brownish hair,
brownish hair.
About yea high, no
mustache or anything,
and, oh, yeah, he
was strong, muscular.
Very athletic.
And he drove a
kind of a darkish,
darkish, American-made,
midsize car.
Don't know about the car,
but the description
sounds like Dave.
He lives in that
motel over there.
Always orders ribs
and wonton soup.
You-you wouldn't
know his room number?
We climb those stairs
often enough. 310.
310.310.
310. Come on.
Anybody there?
- Break down the door.
- Break down the door?
Break down the door!
- Follow him.
- Follow him?
Follow him!
Did-did you see him?
Did you see him?!
Were you that good
a shot in Vietnam?
Better.
I represent Ben Matlock.
I know why you're here.
Arthur Prescott called you.
We're friends...
Me, Art, Gilbert
Lehman, Raymond Price.
We're all friends.
What's the matter,
Art talking too fast when
he explained that to you?
Guess I just like hearing
it from the horse's mouth.
Let me tell you something.
I got a son.
Four years ago,
he needed surgery.
Even with insurance, the
medical bills would have killed us.
Now guess who
paid them off for us?
Raymond Price.
But, like you said, it
was four years ago.
You know, Art seems to
think you're pretty hot stuff.
Now me, I think
you're a pain in the ass.
He, uh, ordered a drink,
told me a Judge Price was dead
and and then
called him a jackass.
Do you always remember things
your customers say so clearly?
Well, I do when
they try to stiff me
for the drinks they order.
So he refused to
pay for his drink?
Yeah. I threw him out.
I suppose an event such as that
would tend to
stick in one's mind.
Thank you.
Your witness, Counselor.
Isn't it likely that another
reason you remember
what he said so clearly was
because of the strange way
he was acting when he
entered your establishment?
What do you mean?
Well, he slurred his words,
he was loud, he staggered.
He acted intoxicated, didn't he?
No.
I beg your pardon?
He seemed a little high maybe,
but he certainly
did not seem drunk.
If he had, I wouldn't
have served him.
Serving drunks is illegal.
No further questions.
Mrs. Hawkins, I'm
real busy right now.
What is it?
You're gonna be in a
lot of trouble, Mr. Matlock.
Gonna be? Gonna be?!
I just want to tell you
how you can avoid it.
What you have to do is focus
on reliability and durability.
You'll say "It's not
easy, but I can do it."
Hello? Hello?
Wearing a suit is one thing,
but shaving... I don't know.
Look at it as a
way to leave behind
what you were and begin afresh.
You know what tomorrow is?
The first day of
the rest of your life.
That's really beautiful, Ben.
Where did you get that?
Off a greeting card.
Mr. Sloan, would you
please tell the court
what you saw on the
night of October 9?
Well, I saw that man
there... Mr. Matlock...
Go into Angels Tavern.
What else did you see?
And I saw him come
out of Angels Tavern.
No, I mean before that.
Before that?
I was just hanging out,
minding my own business.
Um...
perhaps I'm not
being clear, Mr. Sloan.
When was the first time you
saw Mr. Matlock that night?
You know, when he
went into Angels Tavern.
Prior to that, you
saw Mr. Matlock
being dragged from a car
into a warehouse, did you not?
No.
You saw Mr. Matlock
leave that warehouse
in a drugged
condition, did you not?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You're lying, Andrew!
Mr. Matlock...
You-you sold out, didn't you?
You did see the man
- I was chasing...
- Mr. Matlock...
Sit down, Ben.
Only instead of blowing
the whistle, you cut a deal
- with him, didn't you?!
- Mr. Matlock, sit down!
- You cut a deal with him!
- Bailiff.
- Sit down, Ben.
He cut a deal with
him, Your Honor.
Mr. Matlock, another
outburst like that,
and I will have you
placed in restraints
for the rest of this
trial. Am I understood?
But he cut a deal with him!
Proceed, Counselor.
No further questions.
Wish to cross?
No, Your Honor.
Witness may step down.
You cut a deal with him,
and I'll get you for that.
Mr. Matlock.
Conrad, they still here?
Yeah, barely.
Come on, let's go around.
When Sloan walked
out of the courthouse,
he hailed a cab and
came straight here.
Recognize his friend?
That's him. That's the killer.
I'll call the police.
All's I want is my money
so I can get out of here.
What's in those things, anyway?
I'll show you.
Andrew!
Conrad, you all right?
Yeah...
Well... there goes the killer.
We'll check.
All right, move him in.
People here say his
real name is Walker,
Scott Walker.
That's his plane.
According to the
flight plan he filed,
he was headed to Catalina today.
Well, he could be
anywhere by now.
He took that left turn.
Maybe he went
to Central America.
- Think he's smuggling drugs?
- Who knows?
His room was clean as a whistle.
I asked the people at his
motel about his phone bill.
He made four phone
calls in three days
to someone at the Lucinda
Bar in Downtown L.A.
Maybe Conrad
ought to look into that.
I was just thinking that.
Might be interesting
to take a look
at all our suspects'
phone bills.
See if they have a person
or a place in common.
I was just thinking that, too.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
My name is Michelle Thomas.
I'd like to see copies
of the office phone bills
for the past six months,
if you don't mind.
Do you work here?
You haven't been told
about the independent audit
that Watson and Taft
has been hired to perform?
No.
Oh.
Well, the senior
partners are concerned
that the firm's office expenses
seem to be spiraling
out of control.
How far back do
you want me to go?
The last six months.
Okay.
You want 'em, you got 'em.
Have a seat.
Oh, thank you.
How about a beer?
We don't have any.
He's got a beer.
He got the last one.
I see... You don't
serve strangers.
This is a neighborhood bar.
What I really want is a job.
I'm a bartender.
Who do I talk to?
Try the man in the moon.
Ow!
These are dangerous times.
You could break your hand
and leave this place
with nobody to fill in.
You ever think about that?
Hmm?
The problem is, my friend,
my customers prefer drinks
you've probably never heard of.
Try me.
A zombie, a Perfect Rob
Roy and a Suffering Bastard.
Coming up.
Zombie...
Perfect Rob Roy...
Suffering Bastard.
My name is Carlos Berman.
You can call me Carl.
All my employees do.
♪♪
Well, thanks.
That's very nice of you.
I made a call while I was
out to Watson and Taft,
just to check.
No one would confirm the audit?
That's right.
Well, it's a secret.
No one there has ever heard
of Michelle Thomas either.
I'm an attorney.
I need to find out
as much as I can
about Arthur Prescott.
Are you going to
make trouble for him?
That's not my intent,
but to be honest,
it is a possibility.
Forget his phone bills.
How would you like to
get into his beach house?
You could do that?
1:00 tomorrow.
Pacific Coast Highway to Malibu.
I'll meet you there.
He'll be at lunch.
At the risk of my
sounding ungrateful,
why are you doing this?
He's a pig.
Not good enough.
Out in 48 hours guaranteed,
or I talk to somebody else.
FBI! Everybody stay put!
Keep calm and
nobody will get hurt!
Turn the lights back on!
Turn the damn lights
on or we'll start shooting!
You, put your hands up.
Come out from behind there.
That little trick
with the light switch
has earned you a
night behind bars.
Come on, get up.
Let's go. Come on!
You, too, let's go.
What are you waiting for?
You're the guest of honor.
What's the charge
this time, Agent Wilson?
I thought I'd surprise you.
Let's go.
Hey, what is this?
Where's my phone call?
Don't I get to
talk to my lawyer?
My attorney's on his way.
He'll take care of you.
I appreciate what you did.
Getting rousted is an
inconvenience for me.
For my associate, it
would have been a disaster.
This happens to
you all the time?
As soldiers in the
illustrious war against drugs,
they have a need for an enemy,
someone they can hunt
down, capture, interrogate,
report on to their superiors.
One who will justify their
paychecks and pension plans.
That's you?
I'm tangible, you see.
Poverty and prejudice are not.
Gentlemen...
Let's go, Carlos.
Time to talk.
I'd just as soon have
my attorney present.
Well, he got picked
up on his way over here
for speeding or something.
We're going to have
to start without him.
And the backhand's okay,
but this is not working.
Yeah.
Any net time tomorrow?
Yeah, sure. Just
work on that forehand.
I will, yeah.
That's the problem.
It's just... it's
that elbow I think.
- I don't know. I'm not sure.
- It's the follow-through.
- Uh, Dr. Lehman.
- Hmm?
Ben Matlock.
Uh, catch you later.
We sort of met
on the golf course
- the day Judge Price was killed.
- Yeah.
Could I talk with
you for a minute?
Your investigators
already paid me a visit.
I know, but that
was something else.
Sit down, please.
Have some lemonade.
Um, there's a drug, oxynol,
it's a hallucinogen.
It was developed
secretly by our government
in the early '60s, to
make the enemy talk.
I'm familiar with it.
If I'm not mistaken,
the only place it was actually
used was in Cambodia.
Um, Special Forces were sent
in to-to set up for an invasion.
I believe mostly
Green Beret units.
Could you tell me about it?
Well, I could try.
Uh, suppose a person
were injected with it,
what would happen?
He'd become disoriented,
unable to think clearly.
He'd suffer short-term memory
loss, be very suggestible.
Would he appear to be drunk?
Extremely.
Have you ever had
occasion to use oxynol
on one of your patients?
Nope.
Thanks for the lemonade.
Give him the keys.
What are you talking about?
Ah, come on...
All right, all right.
Get in!
Hello, Michelle.
I know this isn't
what you expected
but come in, please.
This was all a setup?
Linda, the woman you spoke
to in the accounting office,
she's, uh, well, she came
straight to me that day.
She's a very loyal girl.
Why didn't you come to
me? I have nothing to hide.
It was your idea to come here?
Well, I thought it'd
give us a chance
to get to know each other.
- I don't think so.
- Oh, come on.
We'll talk, we'll eat,
and then later I'll show
you all my phone bills.
Come on, a little crab
salad, some Chardonnay?
Let me take your jacket.
Make it fast.
I don't know how
long I can keep her.
Call me as soon as you get back.
Right.
♪♪
Don't you think so?
If you like this one, this...
Uh, uh, I've got to
use your bathroom.
I'm sorry, our restroom
is not open to the public.
But I'm...
I'm diabetic and
I've got to take a pill.
I could go into insulin
shock any minute.
I'm sorry.
The last time this happened,
I skipped the shock part
altogether and went straight
into a coma right
there in the shoe store.
Behind the counter
and to your left.
- Thank you, thank you.
- Sure.
You cut us off now,
we'll be destroyed forever.
It's a lost cause, Rahmad.
Maybe it's time
you admitted it, too.
You gave your word.
For six months we've
been giving you support.
What have we got to show for it?
Nothing. You squandered it.
Now it's getting too hot.
This is the end of it.
Caught him listening
outside the door.
Anybody know who he is?
Unfortunately, I do.
I caught 27 trout that day.
That is almost
five fish an hour.
Mr. Prescott, you've talked
about everything under the sun,
and I realize you
love fly-fishing,
but I get the feeling you're
being deliberately evasive.
Evasive, no.
I'm, uh, just a little nervous.
I, uh, I like you.
What about the phone bills?
Look, why don't we discuss
that over some dessert, huh?
Mr. Prescott, would you
please get my jacket?
Just a second.
Hello?
Yeah, look, can I
get right back to you?
Thanks.
I'll get your jacket.
Did you find anything?
There's nothing in her room that
incriminates you or anyone else.
We're home free.
Here you go.
Thanks. And thanks for lunch.
The salad was terrific.
Well, I'll be sure to
tell my housekeeper.
Oh, I almost forgot.
I wanted to ask
you about oxynol.
About what?
The drug you had
access to in Vietnam.
Oxynol, the hallucinogen.
The problem is I really
don't have time right now.
Guess it'll have to wait.
Like the phone bills.
Remember your name yet?
Uh... Uh, it's B-Bat...
Bat... Uh, Batl...
L... No, no, no.
Uh, wait, it's Ben, Ben Matlock.
- Benjamin Matlock?
- Yeah.
This is that lawyer accused
of killing Judge Price.
Seedy looking bum.
Do you know my mother
wanted me to go to law school?
Ben?
Conrad?
Where are you guys?
So, how did it go?
The usual.
Wilson tried to get me
to tell him what I know
about drug trafficking in the
city and as usual, he failed.
I must admit, I was glad
when my attorney
finally showed up.
You want something?
Coffee.
Okay.
Coming up.
My attorney tells me
that you have no criminal
record in California.
I've kept my nose clean...
and I'm not from California.
Then how did you
find out about my bar?
- Friends.
- Who?
I was told that if an
enterprising type of guy
wanted to get
ahead in this town,
this was the place to come.
You want names,
I don't do names.
I forget names as
soon as I hear them.
An enterprising young
man with a clean nose.
You could prove
very useful to me.
Yeah?
I have some business
to attend to this evening.
- Why don't you come along?
- Okay.
I'll call my girlfriend, we
were gonna go to dinner.
Business before pleasure.
Call her afterwards.
All right, come on, stay
in line, keep moving.
My lawyer here yet?
Hey.
- Hey.
- Hmm?
- Hey, wake up.
- Hmm! Hmm.
Got a visitor.
- Hey!
- Hmm...
Are you all right?
Here, sit down.
What happened?
Somebody drugged you again.
Only this time, you went
wandering around in the
middle of the San Diego freeway.
I did?
Yeah.
Highway Patrol turned you
over to Lieutenant Myerson.
He's the one who called me.
You'd passed out by then.
Ooh, see that?
They shot me up and
threw me on a freeway?
Ben, who did this to you?
Where were you today?
Well, I talked to Dr. Lehman
at the country club,
and followed him
to a clothing store
and I-I heard him
arguing with somebody.
Then what?
I don't know. Somebody
must've hit me.
Ooh, left a goose
egg the size of Ohio.
You think Dr. Lehman
drugged you?
Well, he could've.
Could've been any one
of those ex-Green Berets.
They all knew about the drug.
I think they were all involved.
Listen to this.
I was in Arthur Prescott's
beach house today.
I borrowed the tape that
was in his answering machine.
We're getting together
at the warehouse.
North Venice, 6:00 p.m.
I interviewed Daryl Wilson.
I'm willing to bet that was him.
6:00. That's...
That's no more than a
couple of hours away.
We're getting together
at the warehouse.
North Venice, 6:00 p.m.
That's it?
Short and sweet.
It could've been an
invitation to a party.
I'm almost positive the
man who left that message
was Daryl Wilson.
- The FBI agent?
- Yep.
You guys are great.
Where did you get the tape?
- I borrowed it.
- She borrowed it.
Lieutenant,
I'm telling you something
very big, very important
is gonna take place at that
warehouse this afternoon,
and I intend to be there.
It's a free country.
Could be pretty embarrassing,
if what I find out
blows this case apart.
I'll take my chances.
Reporters calling from
all over the country.
I'll have to tell them that
apathy on the part of a certain
police lieutenant forced me to
take matters into my own hands.
You spell your last
name with one "E" or two?
Should be here right away.
What do you know...
It's Carlos Berman.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- He's a very big drug boy.
Now this is getting interesting.
An FBI agent is involved.
Yeah, up to his ears.
The guy with him
killed Judge Price.
What the hell is he doing here?!
Conrad! Get down!
- Police officers, freeze!
- Hold it!
Hold your fire!
- Hold your fire!
All right, everybody,
come out with your hands up now.
Drop your weapons!
Now keep them high!
Keep them where we can see them!
Arms behind your back!
Conrad, are you all right?
- Oh, yeah, I'm fine.
- What the hell you doing here?
When I saw you
get out of that car,
I thought I was seeing things.
- Ben.
- What?
So, they're all set to give
Berman 500 pounds of cocaine,
and he's all set to give them
close to $8 million in cash.
Some system.
Hello?
Hey, Mrs. Hawkins. Yeah,
hang on, he's right here.
Yeah, Mrs. Hawkins?
Good news, Mr. Matlock.
Now, don't hang
up, listen to this.
Here's your horoscope for today.
Ready?
"A new day is dawning.
"Time to revitalize
and refurbish.
Brighten the corner
where you are."
Mrs. Hawkins... So,
you know what I did?
I bought new drapes and
a new spread and sheets
and towels at Macy's, and I
charged them to your account.
Luckily, they were
having a white sale.
Mrs. Hawkins, you had
no business going out...
Hello?
Hello?!
I'll shut up.
Now, let's see,
I guess... I guess the
way these guys worked...
Hello?
I guess the way
they worked was...
they'd sell their
guns for-for drugs,
and then this fellow, Walker,
would smuggle the drugs
up from Central America
in that plane of his,
and he'd get word
to Daryl Wilson,
and this Wilson then
would pretend to roust
Carlos Berman so the
two of them could set up
transfer, and then Wilson
could call the others
with the time and the place,
you know, the warehouse.
That was Lieutenant Myerson.
He said the bullet that
killed Scott Walker was a .45.
Did you see a .45?
The police were carrying
nine millimeter
Berettas and shotguns.
Carlos Berman's men
were carrying Uzis.
Well, if he was shot with a .45,
somebody there
must've had a .45.
Hello, Mr. Prescott.
Michelle, what brings you here?
As I recall from that
picture you showed me,
you and your friends
carried .45s in Vietnam?
I'm not gonna deny that.
Still have yours?
Yes.
I have a subpoena for it.
Would you turn it over
to Officer Landau, please?
Certainly.
I understand the party you
were at last night got pretty wild.
No comment.
You keep it in your office?
Some of my patients
tend to get violent.
- You never know.
- So you're always prepared.
That's how I got
through Vietnam.
Luck had something
to do with that, Doctor.
I sure hope yours
hasn't run out.
What do you want it for?
Come to court
tomorrow and you'll see.
I heard the department
kind of laid you off.
Well, I'll be reinstated just
as soon as this is cleared up.
Now get the hell out.
Sit down. There you go.
Well...
- what is this?
- Open it.
Oh.
It's beautiful.
All right, Ben, what's going on?
Well, that's just my
way of thanking you
for dropping everything at home
and flying out
here to help me out.
You're welcome, but it's my job.
You're a wonderful
lawyer, Michelle.
You're smart, capable.
Of course, you know that.
Thank you.
And-and you know
that I know that.
Yeah.
Ben, what is going on?
You're gonna hate this.
How do you know
until you tell me?
I want to take over
my own defense.
Now, now, this is
no reflection on you.
You're a wonderful lawyer.
Smart and capable.
But did you always tell me
that a lawyer who
defends himself has a fool
- for a client?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And-and-and most
of the time, that's true.
But this is different.
What's different is that
you don't trust
me to defend you.
I knew it, I knew it, I knew it.
I-I-I knew you'd think that way.
What else would I think?
Michelle, this has
nothing to do with you.
It's just with me.
Oh, Ben, you're
not making sense.
I always make sense.
I'm a rational, reasonable man.
Then why do you
want to defend yourself?
All right.
One, I know all the facts.
Two, I'm fully prepared.
Three, I'm totally objective.
And four, some lowlife jackass
is trying to frame
me with murder,
and I'll not get another
decent night's sleep
until I personally pin
his hide to the wall.
That's really rational, Ben.
Good.
I'm glad you understand.
We make a wonderful team.
Your Honor, at this time,
Mr. Matlock would like to
assume his own defense.
As you're aware, my client is
a member of the California Bar
with a great deal of
experience in criminal law.
You are aware of the seriousness
of the charges against
you, Mr. Matlock,
as well as the dangers
of representing
yourself in this matter?
Yea, sir, I am.
I've tried to dissuade
my client, Your Honor,
but Mr. Matlock insists.
It's your decision.
Call your first witness.
I call Arthur Prescott.
You, Dr. Gilbert Lehman,
FBI Agent Daryl Wilson and
the deceased, Judge Price,
all served in Vietnam
together, didn't you?
That's correct.
And you spent much of
the time while you were there
behind enemy lines,
risking your lives for
your country, didn't you?
Well, we did our jobs, yes.
Yeah.
And when it became
apparent that the United States
had failed to achieve what
you were willing to die for,
what so many had died for,
how did you feel, betrayed?
Well, it's hard to
feel your friends
are dying for
nothing, Mr. Matlock.
- Yes, I felt betrayed.
- Yeah.
"I believe the government
of the United States
"reneged on its
inherent obligation
"to democracy in Vietnam
"and has been reneging
on that obligation
in countries all over
the world ever since."
Is that how you felt?
If I'm not mistaken,
you just quoted from a
speech made by Raymond Price
about a year ago at
the local Bar Association.
That's true, but those are
your sentiments, aren't they?
I suppose they are, yes.
And when the congress
cut off all military supplies
to the forces of democracy
struggling in Central America,
how did that make you feel?
I was angry.
So angry, you decided to do
something about it, didn't you?
What do you mean?
You and your friends,
those same four,
used your military connections
to procure field artillery,
and you sold that artillery
covertly and illegally
to the forces you backed in
Central America, didn't you?
- Of course not.
- Only your fighters
didn't pay you with money,
they paid you with cocaine,
which you in turn sold
to... Carlos Berman...
A man with whom you
rendezvoused two nights ago.
Isn't that right?
I'm afraid I'll have to refuse
to answer that question
on the grounds that it
might tend to incriminate me.
What did you do with
all the millions of dollars
you made in the
last couple years
with such transactions?
I have to refuse to answer
that question as well
- on the grounds it might tend to...
- Okay, okay, okay,
okay, okay, okay.
Answer me this.
You didn't do it
for profit, did you?
You were patriots.
The four of you, as a group,
in the last year and a half
have sent to rebel
forces in the Middle East
nearly $12 million to
overthrow a government
which you considered nothing
but a religious dictatorship.
That's absurd.
Not according to Rahmad Hussein.
Remember? The man who owns
the clothing store in Beverly Hills.
He's prepared to
testify that you used
his contacts in the Middle
East to do exactly that.
If he wants to perjure
himself, that's his problem.
Only after awhile when
you realized you were
supporting a... a
hopeless cause...
Both in Central America
and the Middle East...
You decided, "The
hell with them."
You decided to
call it quits, pull out.
But this whole guns for
drugs for money operation
had proved so successful,
you decided to try
it one more time.
Only this time,
you were going to keep all
the money for yourselves.
But Judge Price was a patriot,
a real patriot, and he refused
- to go along with you.
- Objection...
So you had him killed and framed
me for his murder, didn't you?
I've been patient, but this
whole line of questioning
is grossly irrelevant
and has now swung
into bare speculation
and unsupported innuendo.
Your Honor, the questions
I am asking and must ask,
are critical to my defense.
Against my better judgment,
I'm going to allow
you to continue.
Objection overruled
without prejudice.
The People have
a continuing objection to all
lines of question in this area.
A couple days ago,
in, uh, that brouhaha
that your constitutional rights
keeps you from talking
about, a man was killed.
A man named Scott Walker.
Now, he's the man that you hired
to do all your hands-on
dirty work, isn't he?
- No.
- Dirty work that finally
resulted in killing Judge Price.
- No!
- But when you finally realized
that he was going to be
arrested and probably coerced
into telling that you had
hired him to kill Judge Price,
you killed him.
I did no such thing.
Objection, Your Honor.
How far can we let this
- questioning go?
- A few more moments.
Overruled.
Uh, all four of you were issued
.45 caliber sidearms in
Vietnam, were you not?
Yes, we were.
Do you still have yours?
I did until you subpoenaed it.
I subpoenaed all
your friends' guns.
If I told you that
police ballistics
proved that the gun retrieved
from Dr. Lehman's office
is the murder weapon,
would you be surprised?
Well, I-I'd be...
disappointed if Gilbert
was involved in a murder.
But if that's Gilbert's
gun, why am I up here?
Because it's not his gun.
His gun was stolen two years
ago... you didn't know that...
And he went out and
bought another .45.
And according to the
serial number on file
at the gun shop where
he bought his new gun,
this is not his gun.
His gun... is the
gun you gave us.
Now, how do you
suppose that happened?
You switched guns
with him, didn't you?
You knew the police
would discover that Walker
had been shot with a .45.
So, after you shot
him, you hid your gun.
The next day when you made bail,
you went back and retrieved it.
Took it over to
Dr. Lehman's office,
and unbeknownst to him,
switched guns with him.
And that's how this gun,
the murder weapon, your gun,
wound up in
Dr. Lehman's possession
and your gun, his
gun, wound up in yours.
That doesn't prove
that I murdered anyone.
This court is only interested in
whether I murdered someone.
And I believe what you have
done makes that highly unlikely.
As for you, Mr. Prescott,
the City of Los Angeles has
a very fine police department.
They'll connect you
with Scott Walker.
They'll prove that you gave him
the drug that was
administered to me.
And sooner or later, they'll
prove you killed the man
you stood beside in the
jungles of Southeast Asia,
a man on whom you depended,
a man you called friend.
Ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
Hope it's a good
day for Geminis.
What is your verdict?
We find the
defendant not guilty.
Thank you ladies and
gentlemen of the jury.
Mr. Matlock, you stand
acquitted of these charges.
You're free to go.
Court is adjourned.
Yeah. Want a hot dog?
I'll buy. In Atlanta.
Wait a minute.
I wonder if we should
call Mrs. Hawkins
to see if it's a
good day to travel.
Oh, the hell with
it. Let's go home.
www.tvsubtitles.net